<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
    <!--
	<info>
		<name>Unearthed Arcana: Modifying Classes</name>
		<description>Sometimes a campaign will have special needs for archetypes or character options not found in the existing official material. If you’re in this situation, you might want to modify one or more of the classes in the game in order to provide options for players looking for a unique twist on their characters’ abilities. However, modifying a class is not something that should be undertaken lightly, and the job requires some serious effort, playtesting, and revision to get it right. The two best ways to modify a class are to swap out some class features for different ones, and to add new to an existing class. This article presents methods that will help you to use existing mechanics as a model, while drawing upon features of other classes for inspiration.</description>
		<author url="https://dnd.wizards.com/articles/unearthed-arcana/modifying-classes">Wizards of the Coast</author>
		<update version="0.0.1">
			<file name="20150406.xml" url="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/aurorabuilder/elements/master/unearthed-arcana/2015/20150406.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>
     -->
	
	<element name="Unearthed Arcana: Modifying Classes" type="Source" source="Core" id="ID_WOTC_SOURCE_UNEARTHED_ARCANA_20150406">
		<description>
			<p>Sometimes a campaign will have special needs for archetypes or character options not found in the existing official material. If you’re in this situation, you might want to modify one or more of the classes in the game in order to provide options for players looking for a unique twist on their characters’ abilities. However, modifying a class is not something that should be undertaken lightly, and the job requires some serious effort, playtesting, and revision to get it right. The two best ways to modify a class are to swap out some class features for different ones, and to add new to an existing class. This article presents methods that will help you to use existing mechanics as a model, while drawing upon features of other classes for inspiration.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="abbreviation">UA20150406</set>
			<set name="url">https://dnd.wizards.com/articles/unearthed-arcana/modifying-classes</set>
			<set name="author" abbreviation="WOTC" url="http://dnd.wizards.com">Wizards of the Coast</set>
			<set name="official">true</set>
			<set name="playtest">true</set>
			<set name="release">20150406</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<!-- Rule Element-->
	<element name="Rangers With No Spells" type="Rule" source="Unearthed Arcana: Modifying Classes" id="ID_WOTC_UA20150406_RULE_RANGERS_WITH_NO_SPELLS">
		<description>
			<p>As an example of what the class feature replacement process might be like, we will remove spellcasting from the ranger class. Let’s say that in your campaign you want rangers to be a little bit more like Strider from the <i>Lord of the Rings</i>, and less overtly magical from the outset.</p>
			<p class="indent">The Spellcasting class feature has a big impact on the ranger class, so this is no small project. Start by evaluating what the Spellcasting feature is contributing to the class. In general, rangers have a more limited spell list (and know only a relatively small number of spells), and operate on the same half-speed progression for spellcasting as the paladin does. Looking over the ranger’s spells, you might come to the following conclusions about what the Spellcasting feature contributes to the class:</p>
			<ul>
				<li>Rangers have a lot of exploration utility in their spells, with access to magic such as <i>detect poison and disease, beast sense,</i> and <i>conjure animals.</i></li>
				<li>Rangers gain a lot of their combat potency from spells, especially <i>hunter’s mark.</i></li>
				<li>Rangers get some healing and restoration ability from spells such as <i>cure wounds, lesser restoration,</i> and <i>protection from poison</i>, which stave off the harm an adventurer might suffer while exploring in the wilderness.</li>
				<li>Rangers get some combat control effects from their spells such as <i>ensnaring strike, spike growth,</i> and <i>conjure barrage</i>, all of which give the ranger a magical edge in combat.</li>
				<li>At some levels at which the ranger gains access to new spell levels, this is the only class feature the character receives. As a result, the ranger will need additional class features at those levels to prevent them from providing nothing to the ranger aside from increased hit points.</li>
			</ul>
			<p>Given the usefulness of the <i>cure wounds</i> spell, and the greater need for healing at lower levels, let’s create a healing class feature that allows the ranger to create and apply herbal poultices — an improvement that is on par with drinking a potion at first, but one that will scale up as the ranger gains levels.</p>
			<p class="indent">Additionally, since the ranger is likely to need some extra combat utility that spells would normally provide, let’s add a version of the Combat Superiority class feature drawn from the Battle Master fighter. The maneuvers that Combat Superiority grants can provide a nice boost in combat, especially in matters of battlefield control. Looking at the fighter class, we can see that the Battle Master fighter’s Combat Superiority is sitting in a similar space as the spellcasting progression of the Eldritch Knight. We don’t want the ranger to outshine the Battle Master fighter, so we’re going to start the ranger with fewer maneuvers, scaling up as the ranger gains levels. Since we’re going to be replacing a one-half spellcasting progression, this means that we’ll need a few other features to bring this ranger up to par.</p>
			<p class="indent">At 9th and 13th levels are gaps where we can place some exploration-focused mechanics. Let’s model the first one on the <i>protection from poison</i> spell, and also give the poultice-creating class feature an improved effect. The second one we can model on the <i>conjure animals</i> spell, which can be useful both in exploration scenes and in combat scenes.</p>
			<p class="indent">At 17th level is another gap, which we can fix with an improvement on Combat Superiority. Fortunately, the Battle Master has a class feature that would fit in well in the concept of this ranger, so we can swap in the Relentless feature to make sure the ranger always has at least some ability to exercise control over the battlefield, even in the later part of an adventuring day.</p>
			<p class="indent">Finally, we need to consider the impact of these changes on other class features, and make adjustments as necessary. For example, the Beast Master archetype for the ranger has a Share Spells class feature at 15th level that will no longer work without a Spellcasting feature. If your non-spellcasting ranger decides to play a Beast Master, you will need to create a substitute class feature for Share Spells as well, perhaps something to help keep the ranger’s beast companion alive longer. Additionally, since Primeval Awareness requires the ranger to expend spell slots to activate the class feature, we can modify that feature to allow the ranger to use it once and regain its use after finishing a short or long rest.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">Ranger, spell-less</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<!-- Spell-less Ranger -->
	<element name="Spell-less Ranger" type="Class" source="Unearthed Arcana: Modifying Classes" id="ID_WOTC_UA20150406_CLASS_SPELL_LESS_RANGER">
		<description>
			<div element="ID_WOTC_UA20150406_RULE_RANGERS_WITH_NO_SPELLS" />
			<p class="flavor">A warrior who uses martial prowess and knowledge of nature to combat threats on the edges of civilization.</p>
			<p>Rough and wild looking, a human stalks alone through the shadows of trees, hunting the orcs he knows are planning a raid on a nearby farm. Clutching a shortsword in each hand, he becomes a whirlwind of steel, cutting down one enemy after another.</p>
			<p class="indent">After tumbling away from a cone of freezing air, an elf finds her feet and draws back her bow to loose an arrow at the white dragon. Shrugging off the wave of fear that emanates from the dragon like the cold of its breath, she sends one arrow after another to find the gaps between the dragon’s thick scales.</p>
			<p class="indent">Holding his hand high, a half-elf whistles to the hawk that circles high above him, calling the bird back to his side. Whispering instructions in Elvish, he points to the owlbear he’s been tracking and sends the hawk to distract the creature while he readies his bow.</p>
			<p class="indent">Far from the bustle of cities and towns, past the hedges that shelter the most distant farms from the terrors of the wild, amid the dense-packed trees of trackless forests and across wide and empty plains, rangers keep their unending watch.</p>
			<h4>DEADLY HUNTERS</h4>
			<p>Warriors of the wilderness, rangers specialize in hunting the monsters that threaten the edges of civilization—humanoid raiders, rampaging beasts and monstrosities, terrible giants, and deadly dragons. They learn to track their quarry as a predator does, moving stealthily through the wilds and hiding themselves in brush and rubble. Rangers focus their combat training on techniques that are particularly useful against their specific favored foes.</p>
			<h4>INDEPENDENT ADVENTURERS</h4>
			<p>Though a ranger might make a living as a hunter, a guide, or a tracker, a ranger’s true calling is to defend the outskirts of civilization from the ravages of monsters and humanoid hordes that press in from the wild. In some places, rangers gather in secretive orders or join forces with druidic circles. Many rangers, though, are independent almost to a fault, knowing that, when a dragon or a band of orcs attacks, a ranger might be the first—and possibly the last—line of defense.</p>
			<p class="indent">This fierce independence makes rangers well suited to adventuring, since they are accustomed to life far from the comforts of a dry bed and a hot bath. Faced with city-bred adventurers who grouse and whine about the hardships of the wild, rangers respond with some mixture of amusement, frustration, and compassion. But they quickly learn that other adventurers who can carry their own weight in a fight against civilization’s foes are worth any extra burden. Coddled city folk might not know how to feed themselves or find fresh water in the wild, but they make up for it in other ways.</p>
			<h4>CREATING A RANGER</h4>
			<p>As you create your ranger character, consider the nature of the training that gave you your particular capabilities. Did you train with a single mentor, wandering the wilds together until you mastered the ranger’s ways? Did you leave your apprenticeship, or was your mentor slain— perhaps by the same kind of monster that became your favored enemy? Or perhaps you learned your skills as part of a band of rangers affiliated with a druidic circle, trained in mystic paths as well as wilderness lore. You might be self-taught, a recluse who learned combat skills, tracking, and even a magical connection to nature through the necessity of surviving in the wilds.</p>
			<p class="indent">What’s the source of your particular hatred of a certain kind of enemy? Did a monster kill someone you loved or destroy your home village? Or did you see too much of the destruction these monsters cause and commit yourself to reining in their depredations? Is your adventuring career a continuation of your work in protecting the borderlands, or a significant change? What made you join up with a band of adventurers? Do you find it challenging to teach new allies the ways of the wild, or do you welcome the relief from solitude that they offer?</p>
			<h5>QUICK BUILD</h5>
			<p>You can make a ranger quickly by following these suggestions. First, make Dexterity your highest ability score, followed by Wisdom. (Some rangers who focus on two-weapon fighting make Strength higher than Dexterity.) Second, choose the outlander background.</p>
			<h3>CLASS FEATURES</h3>
			<p>As a ranger, you gain the following class features.</p>
			<h5>HIT POINTS</h5>
			<p>
				<span class="emphasis">Hit Dice:</span>1d10 per ranger level
				<br />
				<span class="emphasis">Hit Points at 1st Level:</span>10 + your Constitution modifier
				<br />
				<span class="emphasis">Hit Points at Higher Levels:</span>1d10 (or 6) + your Constitution modifier per ranger level after 1st
				<br />
			</p>
			<h5>PROFICIENCIES</h5>
			<p>
				<span class="emphasis">Armor:</span>Light armor, medium armor, shields
				<br />
				<span class="emphasis">Weapons:</span>Simple weapons, martial weapons
				<br />
				<span class="emphasis">Tools:</span>None
				<br />
			</p>
			<p>
				<span class="emphasis">Saving Throws:</span>Strength, Dexterity
				<br />
				<span class="emphasis">Skills:</span>Choose three skills from Animal Handling, Athletics, Insight, Investigation, Nature, Perception, Stealth, and Survival
				<br />
			</p>
			<h5>EQUIPMENT</h5>
			<p>You start with the following equipment, in addition to the equipment granted by your background:</p>
			<ul>
				<li>
					<i>(a)</i> scale mail or 
					<i>(b)</i> leather armor
				</li>
				<li>
					<i>(a)</i> two shortswords or 
					<i>(b)</i> two simple melee weapons
				</li>
				<li>
					<i>(a)</i> a dungeoneer’s pack or 
					<i>(b)</i> an explorer’s pack
				</li>
				<li>A longbow and a quiver of 20 arrows</li>
			</ul>
			<div element="ID_WOTC_UA20150406_CLASSFEATURE_RANGER_FAVORED_ENEMY" />
			<div element="ID_WOTC_UA20150406_CLASSFEATURE_RANGER_NATURAL_EXPLORER" />
			<div element="ID_WOTC_UA20150406_CLASSFEATURE_RANGER_FIGHTING_STYLE" />
			<div element="ID_WOTC_UA20150406_CLASSFEATURE_RANGER_COMBAT_SUPERIORITY" />
			<div element="ID_WOTC_UA20150406_CLASSFEATURE_RANGER_RANGER_ARCHETYPE" />
			<div element="ID_WOTC_UA20150406_CLASSFEATURE_RANGER_POULTICES" />
			<div element="ID_WOTC_UA20150406_CLASSFEATURE_RANGER_ASI" />
			<div element="ID_WOTC_UA20150406_CLASSFEATURE_RANGER_EXTRA_ATTACK" />
			<div element="ID_WOTC_UA20150406_CLASSFEATURE_RANGER_LANDS_STRIDE" />
			<div element="ID_WOTC_UA20150406_CLASSFEATURE_RANGER_NATURAL_ANTIVENOM" />
			<div element="ID_WOTC_UA20150406_CLASSFEATURE_RANGER_HIDE_IN_PLAIN_SIGHT" />
			<div element="ID_WOTC_UA20150406_CLASSFEATURE_RANGER_CALL_NATURAL_ALLIES" />
			<div element="ID_WOTC_UA20150406_CLASSFEATURE_RANGER_VANISH" />
			<div element="ID_WOTC_UA20150406_CLASSFEATURE_RANGER_RELENTLESS" />
			<div element="ID_WOTC_UA20150406_CLASSFEATURE_RANGER_FERAL_SENSES" />
			<div element="ID_WOTC_UA20150406_CLASSFEATURE_RANGER_FOE_SLAYER" />
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" alt="Ranger">
			<description>A warrior who uses martial prowess and knowledge of nature to combat threats on the edges of civilization.</description>
		</sheet>
		<setters>
			<set name="short">A warrior who uses martial prowess and knowledge of nature to combat threats on the edges of civilization.</set>
			<set name="hd">d10</set>
		</setters>
		<rules>
			<!-- <grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANTS_AVERAGE_HP_D10" /> -->

			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_LIGHT_ARMOR" requirements="!ID_WOTC_UA20150406_PHB_MULTICLASS_RANGER" />
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_MEDIUM_ARMOR" requirements="!ID_WOTC_UA20150406_PHB_MULTICLASS_RANGER" />
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_SHIELDS" requirements="!ID_WOTC_UA20150406_PHB_MULTICLASS_RANGER" />
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_SIMPLE_WEAPONS" requirements="!ID_WOTC_UA20150406_PHB_MULTICLASS_RANGER" />
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_MARTIAL_WEAPONS" requirements="!ID_WOTC_UA20150406_PHB_MULTICLASS_RANGER" />
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_STRENGTH" requirements="!ID_WOTC_UA20150406_PHB_MULTICLASS_RANGER" />
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_SAVINGTHROW_DEXTERITY" requirements="!ID_WOTC_UA20150406_PHB_MULTICLASS_RANGER" />
			<select type="Proficiency" name="Skill Proficiency (Ranger)" supports="Skill,Ranger" number="3" requirements="!ID_WOTC_UA20150406_PHB_MULTICLASS_RANGER" />

			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_WOTC_UA20150406_CLASSFEATURE_RANGER_FAVORED_ENEMY" level="1"/>
			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_WOTC_UA20150406_CLASSFEATURE_RANGER_NATURAL_EXPLORER" level="1"/>
			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_WOTC_UA20150406_CLASSFEATURE_RANGER_FIGHTING_STYLE" level="2"/>
			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_WOTC_UA20150406_CLASSFEATURE_RANGER_COMBAT_SUPERIORITY" level="2"/>
			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_WOTC_UA20150406_CLASSFEATURE_RANGER_RANGER_ARCHETYPE" level="3"/>
			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_WOTC_UA20150406_CLASSFEATURE_RANGER_POULTICES" level="3"/>
			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_WOTC_UA20150406_CLASSFEATURE_RANGER_ASI" level="4"/>
			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_WOTC_UA20150406_CLASSFEATURE_RANGER_EXTRA_ATTACK" level="5"/>
			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_WOTC_UA20150406_CLASSFEATURE_RANGER_LANDS_STRIDE" level="8"/>
			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_WOTC_UA20150406_CLASSFEATURE_RANGER_NATURAL_ANTIVENOM" level="9"/>
			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_WOTC_UA20150406_CLASSFEATURE_RANGER_HIDE_IN_PLAIN_SIGHT" level="10"/>
			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_WOTC_UA20150406_CLASSFEATURE_RANGER_CALL_NATURAL_ALLIES" level="13"/>
			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_WOTC_UA20150406_CLASSFEATURE_RANGER_VANISH" level="14"/>
			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_WOTC_UA20150406_CLASSFEATURE_RANGER_RELENTLESS" level="17"/>
			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_WOTC_UA20150406_CLASSFEATURE_RANGER_FERAL_SENSES" level="18"/>
			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_WOTC_UA20150406_CLASSFEATURE_RANGER_FOE_SLAYER" level="20"/>
		</rules>
		<multiclass id="ID_WOTC_UA20150406_PHB_MULTICLASS_RANGER">
			<prerequisite>Dexterity 13 and Wisdom 13</prerequisite>
			<requirements>([dex:13],[wis:13]),!ID_WOTC_PHB_CLASS_RANGER</requirements>
			<setters>
				<set name="multiclass proficiencies">Light armor, medium armor, shields, simple weapons, martial weapons, one skill from the class’s skill list</set>
			</setters>
			<rules>
				<grant type="Grants" id="ID_INTERNAL_GRANT_MULTICLASS" />

				<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_LIGHT_ARMOR" />
				<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_MEDIUM_ARMOR" />
				<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_SHIELDS" />
				<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_SIMPLE_WEAPONS" />
				<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_MARTIAL_WEAPONS" />
				<select type="Proficiency" name="Skill Proficiency (Ranger)" supports="Skill,Ranger" number="1"/>
			</rules>
		</multiclass>
	</element>
	<element name="Favored Enemy" type="Class Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana: Modifying Classes" id="ID_WOTC_UA20150406_CLASSFEATURE_RANGER_FAVORED_ENEMY">
		<description>
			<p>Beginning at 1st level, you have significant experience studying, tracking, hunting, and even talking to a certain type of enemy.</p>
			<p class="indent">Choose a type of favored enemy: aberrations, beasts, celestials, constructs, dragons, elementals, fey, fiends, giants, monstrosities, oozes, plants, or undead. Alternatively, you can select two races of humanoid (such as gnolls and orcs) as favored enemies.</p>
			<p class="indent">You have advantage on Wisdom (Survival) checks to track your favored enemies, as well as on Intelligence checks to recall information about them.</p>
			<p class="indent">When you gain this feature, you also learn one language of your choice that is spoken by your favored enemies, if they speak one at all.</p>
			<p class="indent">You choose one additional favored enemy, as well as an associated language, at 6th and 14th level. As you gain levels, your choices should reflect the types of monsters you have encountered on your adventures.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You have advantage on Survival checks to track your favored enemies, as well as on Intelligence checks to recall information about them.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<select type="Class Feature" name="Favored Enemy" supports="Favored Enemy" level="1" />
			<select type="Class Feature" name="Favored Enemy" supports="Favored Enemy" level="6" />
			<select type="Class Feature" name="Favored Enemy" supports="Favored Enemy" level="14" />
			<select type="Language" name="Language (Favored Enemy)" level="1" />
			<select type="Language" name="Language (Favored Enemy)" level="6" />
			<select type="Language" name="Language (Favored Enemy)" level="14" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Natural Explorer" type="Class Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana: Modifying Classes" id="ID_WOTC_UA20150406_CLASSFEATURE_RANGER_NATURAL_EXPLORER">
		<description>
			<p>You are particularly familiar with one type of natural environment and are adept at traveling and surviving in such regions. Choose one type of favored terrain: arctic, coast, desert, forest, grassland, mountain, swamp, or the Underdark. When you make an Intelligence or Wisdom check related to your favored terrain, your proficiency bonus is doubled if you are using a skill that you’re proficient in.</p>
			<p class="indent">While traveling for an hour or more in your favored terrain, you gain the following benefits:</p>
			<ul>
				<li>Difficult terrain doesn’t slow your group’s travel.</li>
				<li>Your group can’t become lost except by magical means.</li>
				<li>Even when you are engaged in another activity while traveling (such as foraging, navigating, or tracking), you remain alert to danger.</li>
				<li>If you are traveling alone, you can move stealthily at a normal pace.</li>
				<li>When you forage, you find twice as much food as you normally would.</li>
				<li>While tracking other creatures, you also learn their exact number, their sizes, and how long ago they passed through the area.</li>
			</ul>
			<p class="indent">You choose additional favored terrain types at 6th and 10th level.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>When you make an Intelligence or Wisdom check related to your favored terrain, your proficiency bonus is doubled if you are using a skill that you’re proficient in. While traveling for an hour or more in your favored terrain, you gain benefits.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<select type="Class Feature" name="Favored Terrain" supports="Favored Terrain" level="1" />
			<select type="Class Feature" name="Favored Terrain" supports="Favored Terrain" level="6" />
			<select type="Class Feature" name="Favored Terrain" supports="Favored Terrain" level="10" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Fighting Style" type="Class Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana: Modifying Classes" id="ID_WOTC_UA20150406_CLASSFEATURE_RANGER_FIGHTING_STYLE">
		<description>
			<p>At 2nd level, you adopt a particular style of fighting as your specialty. Choose one of the following options. You can’t take a Fighting Style option more than once, even if you later get to choose again.</p>
			<h5>ARCHERY</h5>
			<p>You gain a +2 bonus to attack rolls you make with ranged weapons.</p>
			<h5>DEFENSE</h5>
			<p>While you are wearing armor, you gain a +1 bonus to AC.</p>
			<h5>DUELING</h5>
			<p>When you are wielding a melee weapon in one hand and no other weapons, you gain a +2 bonus to damage rolls with that weapon.</p>
			<h5>TWO-WEAPON FIGHTING</h5>
			<p>When you engage in two-weapon fighting, you can add your ability modifier to the damage of the second attack.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description></description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<select type="Class Feature" name="Fighting Style" supports="Fighting Style,Ranger" level="2"/>
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Combat Superiority" type="Class Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana: Modifying Classes" id="ID_WOTC_UA20150406_CLASSFEATURE_RANGER_COMBAT_SUPERIORITY">
		<description>
			<p>At 2nd level, you learn maneuvers that are fueled by special dice called superiority dice.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b>Maneuvers.</b> You learn two maneuvers of your choice, which are chosen from the list of maneuvers available to fighters with the Battle Master archetype. Many maneuvers enhance an attack in some way. You can use only one maneuver per attack.</p>
			<p class="indent">You learn one additional maneuver of your choice at 5th, 9th, 13th, and 17th levels. Each time you learn a new maneuver, you can also replace one maneuver you know with a different one.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b>Superiority Dice.</b> You have four superiority dice, which are d8s. A superiority die is expended when you use it. You regain all of your expended superiority dice when you finish a short or long rest.</p>
			<p class="indent">You gain another superiority die at 9th level and one more at 17th level.</p>
			<p class="indent"><b>Saving Throws.</b> Some of your maneuvers require your target to make a saving throw to resist the maneuver’s effects. The saving throw DC is calculated as follows:</p>
			<p><b>Maneuver save DC</b> = 8 + your proficiency bonus + your Strength or Dexterity modifier (your choice).</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You learn maneuvers that are fueled by special dice called superiority dice. You have {{superiority dice:amount}} superiority dice which are d8s. Your DC is {{superiority dice:dc}}.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="superiority dice:amount" value="4" />
			<stat name="superiority dice:amount" value="1" level="9" />
			<stat name="superiority dice:amount" value="1" level="17" />
			<stat name="superiority dice:dc" value="8" />
			<stat name="superiority dice:dc" value="proficiency" />
			<stat name="superiority dice:dc:ability" value="strength:modifier" bonus="ability"/>
			<stat name="superiority dice:dc:ability" value="dexterity:modifier" bonus="ability"/>
			<stat name="superiority dice:dc" value="superiority dice:dc:ability" />
			<select type="Archetype Feature" name="Combat Superiority (Level 2)" supports="Maneuver,Battle Master" number="2" />
			<select type="Archetype Feature" name="Combat Superiority (Level 5)" supports="Maneuver,Battle Master" level="5" />
			<select type="Archetype Feature" name="Combat Superiority (Level 9)" supports="Maneuver,Battle Master" level="9" />
			<select type="Archetype Feature" name="Combat Superiority (Level 13)" supports="Maneuver,Battle Master" level="13" />
			<select type="Archetype Feature" name="Combat Superiority (Level 17)" supports="Maneuver,Battle Master" level="17" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Ranger Archetype" type="Class Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana: Modifying Classes" id="ID_WOTC_UA20150406_CLASSFEATURE_RANGER_RANGER_ARCHETYPE">
		<description>
			<p>At 3rd level, you choose an archetype that you strive to emulate: Hunter or Beast Master, both detailed at the end of the class description. Your choice grants you features at 3rd level and again at 7th, 11th, and 15th level.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description></description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<select type="Archetype" name="Ranger Archetype" supports="Spell-less Ranger" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Poultices" type="Class Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana: Modifying Classes" id="ID_WOTC_UA20150406_CLASSFEATURE_RANGER_POULTICES">
		<description>
			<p>At 3rd level, you can create special herbal poultices that have healing power comparable to some potions. You can spend 1 hour gathering herbs and preparing herbal poultices using treated bandages to create a number of such poultices equal to your Wisdom modifier (minimum 1). You can carry a number of poultices at one time equal to your Wisdom modifier (minimum 1). The poultices you create cannot be applied by anyone but you. After 24 hours, any poultices that you have not used lose their potency.</p>
			<p class="indent">If you spend 1 minute applying one of your poultices to a wounded humanoid creature, thereby expending its use, that creature regains 1d6 hit points for every two ranger levels you have (rounded up).</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You can spend 1 hour gathering herbs and preparing herbal poultices using treated bandages to create a number of such poultices equal to {{poultices:produce and carry}}. You can carry a number of poultices at one time equal to {{poultices:produce and carry}}. The poultices you create cannot be applied by anyone but you. After 24 hours, any poultices that you have not used lose their potency. If you spend 1 minute applying one of your poultices to a wounded humanoid creature, thereby expending its use, that creature regains {{poultices:dice amount}}d6 hit points.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="poultices:produce and carry" value="wisdom:modifier" bonus="base"/>
			<stat name="poultices:produce and carry" value="1" bonus="base"/>
			<stat name="poultices:dice amount" value="level:spell-less ranger:half:up" bonus="base"/>
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Ability Score Improvement (Ranger)" type="Class Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana: Modifying Classes" id="ID_WOTC_UA20150406_CLASSFEATURE_RANGER_ASI">
		<description>
			<p>When you reach 4th level, and again at 8th, 12th, 16th, and 19th level, you can increase one ability score of your choice by 2, or you can increase two ability scores of your choice by 1. As normal, you can’t increase an ability score above 20 using this feature.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false" />
		<rules>
			<!-- <grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_INTERNAL_CLASS_FEATURE_ASI_4_RANGER" level="4" requirements="!ID_INTERNAL_OPTION_ALLOW_FEATS" />
			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_INTERNAL_CLASS_FEATURE_ASI_8_RANGER" level="8" requirements="!ID_INTERNAL_OPTION_ALLOW_FEATS" />
			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_INTERNAL_CLASS_FEATURE_ASI_12_RANGER" level="12" requirements="!ID_INTERNAL_OPTION_ALLOW_FEATS" />
			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_INTERNAL_CLASS_FEATURE_ASI_16_RANGER" level="16" requirements="!ID_INTERNAL_OPTION_ALLOW_FEATS" />
			<grant type="Class Feature" id="ID_INTERNAL_CLASS_FEATURE_ASI_19_RANGER" level="19" requirements="!ID_INTERNAL_OPTION_ALLOW_FEATS" /> -->
			<select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Ranger 4)" supports="Improvement Option,Ranger,4" level="4" />
			<select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Ranger 8)" supports="Improvement Option,Ranger,8" level="8" />
			<select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Ranger 12)" supports="Improvement Option,Ranger,12" level="12" />
			<select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Ranger 16)" supports="Improvement Option,Ranger,16" level="16" />
			<select type="Class Feature" name="Improvement Option (Ranger 19)" supports="Improvement Option,Ranger,19" level="19" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Extra Attack" type="Class Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana: Modifying Classes" id="ID_WOTC_UA20150406_CLASSFEATURE_RANGER_EXTRA_ATTACK">
		<description>
			<p>Beginning at 5th level, you can attack twice, instead of once, whenever you take the Attack action on your turn.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You can attack twice, instead of once, whenever you take the Attack action on your turn.</description>
		</sheet>
	<rules>
		<stat name="extra attack:count" value="2" level="5" bonus="extra attack" />
	</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Land’s Stride" type="Class Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana: Modifying Classes" id="ID_WOTC_UA20150406_CLASSFEATURE_RANGER_LANDS_STRIDE">
		<description>
			<p>Starting at 8th level, moving through nonmagical difficult terrain costs you no extra movement. You can also pass through nonmagical plants without being slowed by them and without taking damage from them if they have thorns, spines, or a similar hazard.</p>
			<p class="indent">In addition, you have advantage on saving throws against plants that are magically created or manipulated to impede movement, such those created by the entangle spell.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>Moving through nonmagical difficult terrain costs you no extra movement. In addition, you have advantage on saving throws against plants that are magically created or manipulated to impede movement, such those created by the entangle spell.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Natural Antivenom" type="Class Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana: Modifying Classes" id="ID_WOTC_UA20150406_CLASSFEATURE_RANGER_NATURAL_ANTIVENOM">
		<description>
			<p>Starting at 9th level, you have advantage on saving throws against poison and have resistance to poison damage. Additionally, you can use one of your poultices to cure one poison effect on the creature you are applying it to, in addition to restoring hit points.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You have advantage on saving throws against poison and you can use one of your poultices to cure one poison effect on the creature you are applying it to, in addition to restoring hit points.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Condition" id="ID_INTERNAL_CONDITION_DAMAGE_RESISTANCE_POISON" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Hide in Plain Sight" type="Class Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana: Modifying Classes" id="ID_WOTC_UA20150406_CLASSFEATURE_RANGER_HIDE_IN_PLAIN_SIGHT">
		<description>
			<p>Starting at 10th level, you can spend 1 minute creating camouflage for yourself. You must have access to fresh mud, dirt, plants, soot, and other naturally occurring materials with which to create your camouflage.</p>
			<p class="indent">Once you are camouflaged in this way, you can try to hide by pressing yourself up against a solid surface, such as a tree or wall, that is at least as tall and wide as you are. You gain a +10 bonus to Dexterity (Stealth) checks as long as you remain there without moving or taking actions. Once you move or take an action or a reaction, you must camouflage yourself again to gain this benefit.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You can spend 1 minute creating camouflage for yourself. You gain a +10 bonus to Stealth checks as long as you remain there without moving or taking actions.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules></rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Call Natural Allies" type="Class Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana: Modifying Classes" id="ID_WOTC_UA20150406_CLASSFEATURE_RANGER_CALL_NATURAL_ALLIES">
		<description>
			<p>Starting at 13th level, when you are in an area of your favored terrain, you can call natural creatures from that terrain to fight on your behalf, using your attunement to the natural world to convince them to aid you. The DM chooses beasts appropriate to the terrain to come to your aid from among those that could hear you and that are within 1 mile of you, in one of the following groups:</p>
			<ul>
				<li>One beast of challenge rating 2 or lower</li>
				<li>Two beasts of challenge rating 1 or lower</li>
				<li>Four beasts of challenge rating 1/2 or lower</li>
				<li>Eight beasts of challenge rating 1/4 or lower</li>
			</ul>
			<p>These beasts approach you from their current location, and will fight alongside you, attacking any creatures that are hostile to you. They are friendly to you and your comrades, and you roll initiative for the called creatures as a group, which takes its own turns. The DM has the creatures’ statistics.</p>
			<p class="indent">After 1 hour, these beasts return to their previous location. Once you use this feature, you cannot use it again in the same general area for 24 hours, since the same animals will not repeatedly heed your call.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>When you are in an area of your favored terrain, you can call natural creatures from that terrain to fight on your behalf, using your attunement to the natural world to convince them to aid you. The DM chooses beasts appropriate to the terrain to come to your aid from among those that could hear you and that are within 1 mile of you, in one of the following groups: One beast of challenge rating 2 or lower; Two beasts of challenge rating 1 or lower; Four beasts of challenge rating 1/2 or lower; Eight beasts of challenge rating 1/4 or lower. They are friendly to you and your comrades, and you roll initiative for the called creatures as a group, which takes its own turns. After 1 hour, these beasts return to their previous location. Once you use this feature, you cannot use it again in the same general area for 24 hours.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Vanish" type="Class Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana: Modifying Classes" id="ID_WOTC_UA20150406_CLASSFEATURE_RANGER_VANISH">
		<description>
			<p>Starting at 14th level, you can use the Hide action as a bonus action on your turn. Also, you can’t be tracked by nonmagical means, unless you choose to leave a trail.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You can use the Hide action as a bonus action on your turn. Also, you can’t be tracked by nonmagical means, unless you choose to leave a trail.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Relentless" type="Class Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana: Modifying Classes" id="ID_WOTC_UA20150406_CLASSFEATURE_RANGER_RELENTLESS">
		<description>
			<p>Starting at 17th level, when you roll initiative and have no superiority dice remaining, you regain 1 superiority die.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>When you roll initiative and have no superiority dice remaining, you regain 1 superiority die.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Feral Senses" type="Class Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana: Modifying Classes" id="ID_WOTC_UA20150406_CLASSFEATURE_RANGER_FERAL_SENSES">
		<description>
			<p>At 18th level, you gain preternatural senses that help you fight creatures you can’t see. When you attack a creature you can’t see, your inability to see it doesn’t impose disadvantage on your attack rolls against it.</p>
			<p class="indent">You are also aware of the location of any invisible creature within 30 feet of you, provided that the creature isn’t hidden from you and you aren’t blinded or deafened.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>When you attack a creature you can’t see, your inability to see it doesn’t impose disadvantage on your attack rolls against it. You are also aware of the location of any invisible creature within 30 feet of you, provided that the creature isn’t hidden from you and you aren’t blinded or deafened.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Foe Slayer" type="Class Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana: Modifying Classes" id="ID_WOTC_UA20150406_CLASSFEATURE_RANGER_FOE_SLAYER">
		<description>
			<p>At 20th level, you become an unparalleled hunter of your enemies. Once on each of your turns, you can add your Wisdom modifier to the attack roll or the damage roll of an attack you make against one of your favored enemies. You can choose to use this feature before or after the roll, but before any effects of the roll are applied.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet usage="1/Turn">
			<description>You can add {{wisdom:modifier}} to the attack roll or the damage roll of an attack you make against one of your favored enemies. You can choose to use this feature before or after the roll, but before any effects of the roll are applied.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>

	<!-- Beast Master -->
	<element name="Beast Master" type="Archetype" source="Unearthed Arcana: Modifying Classes" id="ID_WOTC_UA20150406_RANGER_ARCHETYPE_BEAST_MASTER">
		<supports>Spell-less Ranger</supports>
		<description>
			<p>The Beast Master archetype embodies a friendship between the civilized races and the beasts of the world. United in focus, beast and ranger work as one to fight the monstrous foes that threaten civilization and the wilderness alike. Emulating the Beast Master archetype means committing yourself to this ideal, working in partnership with an animal as its companion and friend.</p>
			<div element="ID_WOTC_UA20150406_RANGER_ARCHETYPE_BEAST_MASTER_RANGERS_COMPANION" />
			<div element="ID_WOTC_UA20150406_RANGER_ARCHETYPE_BEAST_MASTER_EXCEPTIONAL_TRAINING" />
			<div element="ID_WOTC_UA20150406_RANGER_ARCHETYPE_BEAST_MASTER_BESTIAL_FURY" />
			<p>As a replacement for Share Spells, we could also consider the following feature:</p>
			<div element="ID_WOTC_UA20150406_RANGER_ARCHETYPE_BEAST_MASTER_BEASTLY_COORDINATION" />
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>The Beast Master archetype embodies a friendship between the civilized races and the beasts of the world.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_UA20150406_RANGER_ARCHETYPE_BEAST_MASTER_RANGERS_COMPANION" level="3" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_UA20150406_RANGER_ARCHETYPE_BEAST_MASTER_EXCEPTIONAL_TRAINING" level="7" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_UA20150406_RANGER_ARCHETYPE_BEAST_MASTER_BESTIAL_FURY" level="11" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_UA20150406_RANGER_ARCHETYPE_BEAST_MASTER_BEASTLY_COORDINATION" level="15" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Ranger’s Companion" type="Archetype Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana: Modifying Classes" id="ID_WOTC_UA20150406_RANGER_ARCHETYPE_BEAST_MASTER_RANGERS_COMPANION">
		<description>
			<p>At 3rd level, you gain a beast companion that accompanies you on your adventures and is trained to fight alongside you. Choose a beast that is no larger than Medium and that has a challenge rating of 1/4 or lower (appendix D presents statistics for the hawk, mastiff, and panther as examples). Add your proficiency bonus to the beast’s AC, attack rolls, and damage rolls, as well as to any saving throws and skills it is proficient in. Its hit point maximum equals its normal maximum or four times your ranger level, whichever is higher.</p>
			<p class="indent">The beast obeys your commands as best as it can. It takes its turn on your initiative, though it doesn’t take an action unless you command it to. On your turn, you can verbally command the beast where to move (no action required by you). You can use your action to verbally command it to take the Attack, Dash, Disengage, Dodge, or Help action. Once you have the Extra Attack feature, you can make one weapon attack yourself when you command the beast to take the Attack action.</p>
			<p class="indent">While traveling through your favored terrain with only the beast, you can move stealthily at a normal pace.</p>
			<p class="indent">If the beast dies, you can obtain another one by spending 8 hours magically bonding with another beast that isn’t hostile to you, either the same type of beast as before or a different one.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>The beast obeys your commands as best as it can. It takes its turn on your initiative, though it doesn’t take an action unless you command it to. On your turn, you can verbally command the beast where to move (no action required by you). You can use your action to verbally command it to take the Attack, Dash, Disengage, Dodge, or Help action. Once you have the Extra Attack feature, you can make one weapon attack yourself when you command the beast to take the Attack action.
		While traveling through your favored terrain with only the beast, you can move stealthily at a normal pace.
		If the beast dies, you can obtain another one by spending 8 hours magically bonding with another beast that isn’t hostile to you, either the same type of beast as before or a different one.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
		<select type="Companion" name="Ranger’s Companion" supports="Beast,(Tiny||Small||Medium),(1/4||1/8||0)" />
		<stat name="companion:ac" value="proficiency" />
		<stat name="companion:attack" value="proficiency" />
		<stat name="companion:damage" value="proficiency" />
		<!-- 4x ranger level -->
		<stat name="_alternative:hp:max" value="level:ranger" />
		<stat name="_alternative:hp:max" value="level:ranger" />
		<stat name="_alternative:hp:max" value="level:ranger" />
		<stat name="_alternative:hp:max" value="level:ranger" />

		<stat name="companion:hp:max" value="_alternative:hp:max" bonus="base" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Exceptional Training" type="Archetype Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana: Modifying Classes" id="ID_WOTC_UA20150406_RANGER_ARCHETYPE_BEAST_MASTER_EXCEPTIONAL_TRAINING">
		<description>
			<p>Beginning at 7th level, on any of your turns when your beast companion doesn’t attack, you can use a bonus action to command the beast to take the Dash, Disengage, Dodge, or Help action on its turn.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>On any of your turns when your beast companion doesn’t attack, you can use a bonus action to command the beast to take the Dash, Disengage, Dodge, or Help action on its turn.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Bestial Fury" type="Archetype Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana: Modifying Classes" id="ID_WOTC_UA20150406_RANGER_ARCHETYPE_BEAST_MASTER_BESTIAL_FURY">
		<description>
			<p>Starting at 11th level, your beast companion can make two attacks when you command it to use the Attack action.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>Your beast companion can make two attacks when you command it to use the Attack action.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Beastly Coordination" type="Archetype Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana: Modifying Classes" id="ID_WOTC_UA20150406_RANGER_ARCHETYPE_BEAST_MASTER_BEASTLY_COORDINATION">
		<description>
			<p>Beginning at 15th level, when an attacker that you can see hits your beast companion with an attack, you can call out a warning. If your beast companion can hear you, it can use its reaction to halve the attack’s damage against it.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>When an attacker that you can see hits your beast companion with an attack, you can call out a warning. If your beast companion can hear you, it can use its reaction to halve the attack’s damage against it.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>

	<element name="Hunter" type="Archetype" source="Unearthed Arcana: Modifying Classes" id="ID_WOTC_UA20150406_RANGER_ARCHETYPE_HUNTER">
		<supports>Spell-less Ranger</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Emulating the Hunter archetype means accepting your place as a bulwark between civilization and the terrors of the wilderness. As you walk the Hunter’s path, you learn specialized techniques for fighting the threats you face, from rampaging ogres and hordes of orcs to towering giants and terrifying dragons.</p>
			<div element="ID_WOTC_UA20150406_RANGER_ARCHETYPE_HUNTER_HUNTERS_PREY" />
			<div element="ID_WOTC_UA20150406_RANGER_ARCHETYPE_HUNTER_DEFENSIVE_TACTICS" />
			<div element="ID_WOTC_UA20150406_RANGER_ARCHETYPE_HUNTER_MULTIATTACK" />
			<div element="ID_WOTC_UA20150406_RANGER_ARCHETYPE_HUNTER_SUPERIOR_HUNTERS_DEFENSE" />
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>Emulating the Hunter archetype means accepting your place as a bulwark between civilization and the terrors of the wilderness.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_UA20150406_RANGER_ARCHETYPE_HUNTER_HUNTERS_PREY" level="3" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_UA20150406_RANGER_ARCHETYPE_HUNTER_DEFENSIVE_TACTICS" level="7" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_UA20150406_RANGER_ARCHETYPE_HUNTER_MULTIATTACK" level="11" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_UA20150406_RANGER_ARCHETYPE_HUNTER_SUPERIOR_HUNTERS_DEFENSE" level="15" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Hunter’s Prey" type="Archetype Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana: Modifying Classes" id="ID_WOTC_UA20150406_RANGER_ARCHETYPE_HUNTER_HUNTERS_PREY">
		<description>
			<p>At 3rd level, you gain one of the following features of your choice.</p>
			<p>
				<span class="feature">Colossus Slayer.</span>Your tenacity can wear down the most potent foes. When you hit a creature with a weapon attack, the creature takes an extra 1d8 damage if it’s below its hit point maximum. You can deal this extra damage only once per turn.
				<br/>
				<span class="feature">Giant Killer.</span>When a Large or larger creature within 5 feet of you hits or misses you with an attack, you can use your reaction to attack that creature immediately after its attack, provided that you can see the creature.
				<br/>
				<span class="feature">Horde Breaker.</span>Once on each of your turns when you make a weapon attack, you can make another attack with the same weapon against a different creature that is within 5 feet of the original target and within range of your weapon.
				<br/>
			</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description></description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<select type="Archetype Feature" name="Hunter’s Prey" supports="Hunters Pray" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Defensive Tactics" type="Archetype Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana: Modifying Classes" id="ID_WOTC_UA20150406_RANGER_ARCHETYPE_HUNTER_DEFENSIVE_TACTICS">
		<description>
			<p>At 7th level, you gain one of the following features of your choice.</p>
			<p>
				<span class="feature">Escape the Horde.</span>Opportunity attacks against you are made with disadvantage.
				<br/>
				<span class="feature">Multiattack Defense.</span>When a creature hits you with an attack, you gain a +4 bonus to AC against all subsequent attacks made by that creature for the rest of the turn.
				<br/>
				<span class="feature">Steel Will.</span>You have advantage on saving throws against being frightened.
				<br/>
			</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description></description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<select type="Archetype Feature" name="Defensive Tactics" supports="Defensive Tactics" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Multiattack" type="Archetype Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana: Modifying Classes" id="ID_WOTC_UA20150406_RANGER_ARCHETYPE_HUNTER_MULTIATTACK">
		<description>
			<p>At 11th level, you gain one of the following features of your choice.</p>
			<p>
				<span class="feature">Volley.</span>You can use your action to make a ranged attack against any number of creatures within 10 feet of a point you can see within your weapon’s range. You must have ammunition for each target, as normal, and you make a separate attack roll for each target.
				<br/>
				<span class="feature">Whirlwind Attack.</span>You can use your action to make a melee attack against any number of creatures within 5 feet of you, with a separate attack roll for each target.
				<br/>
			</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description></description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<select type="Archetype Feature" name="Multiattack" supports="Multiattack" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Superior Hunter’s Defense" type="Archetype Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana: Modifying Classes" id="ID_WOTC_UA20150406_RANGER_ARCHETYPE_HUNTER_SUPERIOR_HUNTERS_DEFENSE">
		<description>
			<p>At 15th level, you gain one of the following features of your choice.</p>
			<p>
				<span class="feature">Evasion.</span>You can nimbly dodge out of the way of certain area effects, such as a red dragon’s fiery breath or a lightning bolt spell. When you are subjected to an effect that allows you to make a Dexterity saving throw to take only half damage, you instead take no damage if you succeed on the saving throw, and only half damage if you fail.
				<br/>
				<span class="feature">Stand Against the Tide.</span>When a hostile creature misses you with a melee attack, you can use your reaction to force that creature to repeat the same attack against another creature (other than itself) of your choice.
				<br/>
				<span class="feature">Uncanny Dodge.</span>When an attacker that you can see hits you with an attack, you can use your reaction to halve the attack’s damage against you.
				<br/>
			</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description></description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<select type="Archetype Feature" name="Superior Hunter’s Defense" supports="Superior Hunters Defense" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<!-- Rule Element 2-->
	<element name="Favored Soul" type="Rule" source="Unearthed Arcana: Modifying Classes" id="ID_WOTC_UA20150406_RULE_FAVORED_SOUL">
		<description>
			<p>As an example of how creating a new class option could work, let’s examine a design that was a full-fledged class in the third edition supplement <i>Complete Divine</i>: the favored soul. This might be an appealing archetype if you are running a game where the gods are going to have a big impact on the world, and where the Chosen of those gods (individuals bestowed with a fragment of a god’s divine power) are prominent players in the campaign. To reflect this tone, let’s create the Favored Soul as anew origin for the sorcerer class. This decision reflects the idea that the character is someone who is fundamentally changed by the touch of his or her deity, which awakens powerful magical abilities.</p>
			<p class="indent">Looking at the existing sorcerous origins, we can determine that, at 1st level, an origin provides not only the explanation for the source of the sorcerer’s power, but also a flourish on the way that character plays. Since this sorcerer is going to be gaining its magic by being imbued with divine power, we decide to give the Favored Soul access to some spells normally gained by the cleric. Any time we expand the known spells of the sorcerer, we run the risk of overshadowing the other sorcerous origins, since the limitation on the number of spells the sorcerer knows has a big impact on how the class plays. This indicates that the other class features probably shouldn’t all tie closely to the sorcerer’s spellcasting, since that aspect of the sorcerer is already getting quite a boost. Since the favored soul class was a little more martial in its previous incarnation, we decide to give our sorcerer some better armor and access to simple weapons, similar to the defensive bonuses gained by the Draconic Bloodline sorcerer at 1st level.</p>
			<p class="indent">At 6th level, the other sorcerous origins provide features that have an impact on the character’s combat abilities. Looking at the bard class, we can see that the College of Valor gains the Extra Attack class feature at the same level, and we decide to give that to the Favored Soul to further enhance its martial bent.</p>
			<p class="indent">At 14th level, the sorcerous origins provide some measure of utility, with little direct impact on spellcasting or combat capabilities. Here, we choose to model the Favored Soul’s feature after the Draconic Bloodline’s feature at the same level, reflecting the touch of the divine with some imagery typically associated with divinity: wings.</p>
			<p class="indent">At 18th level, the sorcerous origins provide options that are both potent and strongly linked to the origin’s central theme. Since the sorcerer will have access to higher-level spells at this level, and the feature we gave it at 1st level to provide some cleric spells won’t have as much of an impact, we decide to tie this class feature to those cleric spells, both to incentivize the continued use of those spells, and to give the Favored Soul a little more resilience in the face of high-level threats.</p>
		</description>
		<setters>
			<set name="keywords">favored, soul, origin, sorcerous</set>
		</setters>
	</element>

	<!-- Favored Soul -->
	<element name="Favored Soul" type="Archetype" source="Unearthed Arcana: Modifying Classes" id="ID_WOTC_UA20150406_SORCERER_ARCHETYPE_FAVORED_SOUL">
		<supports>Sorcerous Origin</supports>
		<description>
			<div element="ID_WOTC_UA20150406_RULE_FAVORED_SOUL" />
			<p class="indent">When we are done with this initial design, here’s what the Favored Soul sorcerous origin looks like:</p>
			<div element="ID_WOTC_UA20150406_SORCERER_ARCHETYPE_FAVORED_SOUL_CHOSEN_OF_THE_GODS" />
			<div element="ID_WOTC_UA20150406_SORCERER_ARCHETYPE_FAVORED_SOUL_BONUS_PROFICIENCIES" />
			<div element="ID_WOTC_UA20150406_SORCERER_ARCHETYPE_FAVORED_SOUL_EXTRA_ATTACK" />
			<div element="ID_WOTC_UA20150406_SORCERER_ARCHETYPE_FAVORED_SOUL_DIVINE_WINGS" />
			<div element="ID_WOTC_UA20150406_SORCERER_ARCHETYPE_FAVORED_SOUL_POWER_OF_THE_CHOSEN" />
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>Sometimes the spark of magic that fuels a sorcerer comes from a divine source that glimmers within the soul.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_UA20150406_SORCERER_ARCHETYPE_FAVORED_SOUL_CHOSEN_OF_THE_GODS" level="1" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_UA20150406_SORCERER_ARCHETYPE_FAVORED_SOUL_BONUS_PROFICIENCIES" level="1" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_UA20150406_SORCERER_ARCHETYPE_FAVORED_SOUL_EXTRA_ATTACK" level="6" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_UA20150406_SORCERER_ARCHETYPE_FAVORED_SOUL_DIVINE_WINGS" level="14" />
			<grant type="Archetype Feature" id="ID_WOTC_UA20150406_SORCERER_ARCHETYPE_FAVORED_SOUL_POWER_OF_THE_CHOSEN" level="18" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Chosen of the Gods" type="Archetype Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana: Modifying Classes" id="ID_WOTC_UA20150406_SORCERER_ARCHETYPE_FAVORED_SOUL_CHOSEN_OF_THE_GODS">
		<description>
			<p>At 1st level, you choose one of the cleric class’s divine domains. You add that domain’s spells for 1st-level clerics to your known spells. These spells do not count against the number of spells you can know, and they are considered to be sorcerer spells for you. When you reach 3rd, 5th, 7th, and 9th levels in the sorcerer class, you likewise learn your domain’s spells that become available at those levels.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false"/>
		<rules>
			<select type="Archetype Feature" name="Divine Domain (Favored Soul)" supports="Favored Soul Divine Domain" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Bonus Proficiencies" type="Archetype Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana: Modifying Classes" id="ID_WOTC_UA20150406_SORCERER_ARCHETYPE_FAVORED_SOUL_BONUS_PROFICIENCIES">
		<description>
			<p>At 1st level, you gain proficiency in light armor, medium armor, shields, and simple weapons.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet display="false">
			<description></description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_LIGHT_ARMOR" />
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_MEDIUM_ARMOR" />
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_ARMOR_PROFICIENCY_SHIELDS" />
			<grant type="Proficiency" id="ID_PROFICIENCY_WEAPON_PROFICIENCY_SIMPLE_WEAPONS" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Extra Attack" type="Archetype Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana: Modifying Classes" id="ID_WOTC_UA20150406_SORCERER_ARCHETYPE_FAVORED_SOUL_EXTRA_ATTACK">
		<description>
			<p>Starting at 6th level, you can attack twice, instead of once, whenever you take the Attack action on your turn.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>You can attack twice, instead of once, whenever you take the Attack action on your turn</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="extra attack:count" value="2" bonus="extra attack" />
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Divine Wings" type="Archetype Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana: Modifying Classes" id="ID_WOTC_UA20150406_SORCERER_ARCHETYPE_FAVORED_SOUL_DIVINE_WINGS">
		<description>
			<p>At 14th level, you gain the ability to sprout a pair of wings from your back (feathered or bat-like, your choice), gaining a flying speed equal to your current walking speed. You can create these wings as a bonus action on your turn. They last until you dismiss them as a bonus action on your turn.</p>
			<p class="indent">You can’t manifest your wings while wearing armor unless the armor is made to accommodate them, and clothing not made to accommodate your wings might be destroyed when you manifest them.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet action="Bonus Action">
			<description>You can sprout a pair of wings from your back (feathered or bat-like, your choice), gaining a flying speed equal to your current walking speed. They last until you dismiss them as a bonus action on your turn. You can’t manifest your wings while wearing armor unless the armor is made to accommodate them, and clothing not made to accommodate your wings might be destroyed when you manifest them.</description>
		</sheet>
	</element>
	<element name="Power of the Chosen" type="Archetype Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana: Modifying Classes" id="ID_WOTC_UA20150406_SORCERER_ARCHETYPE_FAVORED_SOUL_POWER_OF_THE_CHOSEN">
		<description>
			<p>Starting at 18th level, when you cast one of the spells you learned from your Chosen of the Gods class feature, you regain hit points equal to your Charisma modifier (minimum +1) + the spell’s level.</p>
			<p class="indent">Once you use this feature, you can’t use it again until you finish a long rest.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet usage="1/Long Rest">
			<description>When you cast one of the spells you learned from your Chosen of the Gods class feature, you regain hit points equal to your {{power of the chosen}} + the spell’s level.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<stat name="power of the chosen" value="1" bonus="base" />
			<stat name="power of the chosen" value="charisma:modifier" bonus="base" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<!-- Favored Soul Divine Domain elements-->
	<element name="Knowledge Domain" type="Archetype Feature" source="Player’s Handbook" id="ID_WOTC_UA20150406_PHB_ARCHETYPE_FAVORED_SOUL_KNOWLEDGE_DOMAIN">
		<supports>Favored Soul Divine Domain</supports>
		<description>
			<p>The gods of knowledge—including Oghma, Boccob, Gilean, Aureon, and Thoth—value learning and understanding above all. Some teach that knowledge is to be gathered and shared in libraries and universities, or promote the practical knowledge of craft and invention. Some deities hoard knowledge and keep its secrets to themselves. And some promise their followers that they will gain tremendous power if they unlock the secrets of the multiverse. Followers of these gods study esoteric lore, collect old tomes, delve into the secret places of the earth, and learn all they can. Some gods of knowledge promote the practical knowledge of craft and invention, including smith deities like Gond, Reorx, Onatar, Moradin, Hephaestus, and Goibhniu.</p>
			<h5>Knowledge Domain Spells</h5>
			<table>
				<thead>
					<tr><td>Sorcerer Level</td><td>Spells</td></tr>
				</thead>
				<tr><td>1rd</td><td><em>command, identify</em></td></tr>
				<tr><td>3rd</td><td><em>augury, suggestion</em></td></tr>
				<tr><td>5th</td><td><em>nondetection, speak with dead</em></td></tr>
				<tr><td>7th</td><td><em>arcane eye, confusion</em></td></tr>
				<tr><td>9th</td><td><em>legend lore, scrying</em></td></tr>
			</table>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>The gods of knowledge value learning and understanding above all.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_COMMAND" level="1" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_IDENTIFY" level="1" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_AUGURY" level="3" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SUGGESTION" level="3" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_NONDETECTION" level="5" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SPEAK_WITH_DEAD" level="5" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ARCANE_EYE" level="7" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CONFUSION" level="7" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_LEGEND_LORE" level="9" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SCRYING" level="9" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Life Domain" type="Archetype Feature" source="Player’s Handbook" id="ID_WOTC_UA20150406_PHB_ARCHETYPE_FAVORED_SOUL_LIFE_DOMAIN">
		<supports>Favored Soul Divine Domain</supports>
		<description>
			<p>The Life domain focuses on the vibrant positive energy— one of the fundamental forces of the universe—that sustains all life. The gods of life promote vitality and health through healing the sick and wounded, caring for those in need, and driving away the forces of death and undeath. Almost any non-evil deity can claim influence over this domain, particularly agricultural deities (such as Chauntea, Arawai, and Demeter), sun gods (such as Lathander, Pelor, and Re-Horakhty), gods of healing or endurance (such as Ilmater, Mishakal, Apollo, and Diancecht), and gods of home and community (such as Hestia, Hathor, and Boldrei).</p>
			<h5>Life Domain Spells</h5>
			<table>
				<thead>
					<tr><td>Sorcerer Level</td><td>Spells</td></tr>
				</thead>
				<tr><td>1rd</td><td><em>bless, cure wounds</em></td></tr>
				<tr><td>3rd</td><td><em>lesser restoration, spiritual weapon</em></td></tr>
				<tr><td>5th</td><td><em>beacon of hope, revivify</em></td></tr>
				<tr><td>7th</td><td><em>death ward, guardian of faith</em></td></tr>
				<tr><td>9th</td><td><em>mass cure wounds, raise dead</em></td></tr>
			</table>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>The Life domain focuses on the vibrant positive energy— one of the fundamental forces of the universe—that sustains all life.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BLESS" level="1" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CURE_WOUNDS" level="1" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_LESSER_RESTORATION" level="3" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SPIRITUAL_WEAPON" level="3" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BEACON_OF_HOPE" level="5" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_REVIVIFY" level="5" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DEATH_WARD" level="7" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GUARDIAN_OF_FAITH" level="7" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MASS_CURE_WOUNDS" level="9" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_RAISE_DEAD" level="9" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Light Domain" type="Archetype Feature" source="Player’s Handbook" id="ID_WOTC_UA20150406_PHB_ARCHETYPE_FAVORED_SOUL_LIGHT_DOMAIN">
		<supports>Favored Soul Divine Domain</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Gods of light—including Helm, Lathander, Pholtus, Branchala, the Silver Flame, Belenus, Apollo, and Re-Horakhty—promote the ideals of rebirth and renewal, truth, vigilance, and beauty, often using the symbol of the sun. Some of these gods are portrayed as the sun itself or as a charioteer who guides the sun across the sky. Others are tireless sentinels whose eyes pierce every shadow and see through every deception. Some are deities of beauty and artistry, who teach that art is a vehicle for the soul's improvement. Clerics of a god of light are enlightened souls infused with radiance and the power of their gods’ discerning vision, charged with chasing away lies and burning away darkness.</p>
			<h5>Light Domain Spells</h5>
			<table>
				<thead>
					<tr><td>Sorcerer Level</td><td>Spells</td></tr>
				</thead>
				<tr><td>1rd</td><td><em>burning hands, faerie fire</em></td></tr>
				<tr><td>3rd</td><td><em>flaming sphere, scorching ray</em></td></tr>
				<tr><td>5th</td><td><em>daylight, fireball</em></td></tr>
				<tr><td>7th</td><td><em>guardian of faith, wall of fire</em></td></tr>
				<tr><td>9th</td><td><em>flame strike, scrying</em></td></tr>
			</table>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>Gods of light promote the ideals of rebirth and renewal, truth, vigilance, and beauty, often using the symbol of the sun.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BURNING_HANDS" level="1" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FAERIE_FIRE" level="1" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FLAMING_SPHERE" level="3" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SCORCHING_RAY" level="3" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DAYLIGHT" level="5" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FIREBALL" level="5" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GUARDIAN_OF_FAITH" level="7" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_WALL_OF_FIRE" level="7" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FLAME_STRIKE" level="9" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SCRYING" level="9" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Nature Domain" type="Archetype Feature" source="Player’s Handbook" id="ID_WOTC_UA20150406_PHB_ARCHETYPE_FAVORED_SOUL_NATURE_DOMAIN">
		<supports>Favored Soul Divine Domain</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Gods of nature are as varied as the natural world itself, from inscrutable gods of the deep forests (such as Silvanus, Obad-Hai, Chislev, Balinor, and Pan) to friendly deities associated with particular springs and groves (such as Eldath). Druids revere nature as a whole and might serve one of these deities, practicing mysterious rites and reciting all-but-forgotten prayers in their own secret tongue. But many of these gods have clerics as well, champions who take a more active role in advancing the interests of a particular nature god. These clerics might hunt the evil monstrosities that despoil the woodlands, bless the harvest of the faithful, or wither the crops of those who anger their gods.</p>
			<h5>Nature Domain Spells</h5>
			<table>
				<thead>
					<tr><td>Sorcerer Level</td><td>Spells</td></tr>
				</thead>
				<tr><td>1rd</td><td><em>animal friendship, speak with animals</em></td></tr>
				<tr><td>3rd</td><td><em>barkskin, spike growth</em></td></tr>
				<tr><td>5th</td><td><em>plant growth, wind wall</em></td></tr>
				<tr><td>7th</td><td><em>dominate beast, grasping vine</em></td></tr>
				<tr><td>9th</td><td><em>insect plague, tree stride</em></td></tr>
			</table>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>Gods of nature are as varied as the natural world itself, from inscrutable gods of the deep forests to friendly deities associated with particular springs and groves.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ANIMAL_FRIENDSHIP" level="1" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SPEAK_WITH_ANIMALS" level="1" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BARKSKIN" level="3" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SPIKE_GROWTH" level="3" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PLANT_GROWTH" level="5" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_WIND_WALL" level="5" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DOMINATE_BEAST" level="7" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GRASPING_VINE" level="7" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_INSECT_PLAGUE" level="9" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_TREE_STRIDE" level="9" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Tempest Domain" type="Archetype Feature" source="Player’s Handbook" id="ID_WOTC_UA20150406_PHB_ARCHETYPE_FAVORED_SOUL_TEMPEST_DOMAIN">
		<supports>Favored Soul Divine Domain</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Gods whose portfolios include the Tempest domain - including Talos, Umberlee, Kord, Zeboim, the Devourer, Zeus, and Thor—govern storms, sea, and sky. They include gods of lightning and thunder, gods of earthquakes, some fire gods, and certain gods of violence, physical strength, and courage. In some pantheons, a god of this domain rules over other deities and is known for swift justice delivered by thunderbolts. In the pantheons of seafaring people, gods of this domain are ocean deities and the patrons of sailors. Tempest gods send their clerics to inspire fear in the common folk, either to keep those folk on the path of righteousness or to encourage them to offer sacrifices of propitiation to ward off divine wrath.</p>
			<h5>Tempest Domain Spells</h5>
			<table>
				<thead>
					<tr><td>Sorcerer Level</td><td>Spells</td></tr>
				</thead>
				<tr><td>1rd</td><td><em>fog cloud, thunderwave</em></td></tr>
				<tr><td>3rd</td><td><em>gust of wind, shatter</em></td></tr>
				<tr><td>5th</td><td><em>call lightning, sleet storm</em></td></tr>
				<tr><td>7th</td><td><em>control water, ice storm</em></td></tr>
				<tr><td>9th</td><td><em>destructive wave, insect plague</em></td></tr>
			</table>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>Gods whose portfolios include the Tempest domain govern storms, sea, and sky.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ANIMAL_FOG_CLOUD" level="1" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_THUNDERWAVE" level="1" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GUST_OF_WIND" level="3" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SHATTER" level="3" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CALL_LIGHTNING" level="5" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SLEET_STORM" level="5" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CONTROL_WATER" level="7" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ICE_STORM" level="7" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DESTRUCTIVE_WAVE" level="9" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_INSECT_PLAGUE" level="9" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Trickery Domain" type="Archetype Feature" source="Player’s Handbook" id="ID_WOTC_UA20150406_PHB_ARCHETYPE_FAVORED_SOUL_TRICKERY_DOMAIN">
		<supports>Favored Soul Divine Domain</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Gods of trickery—such as Tymora, Beshaba, Olidammara, the Traveler, Garl Glittergold, and Loki—are mischief-makers and instigators who stand as a constant challenge to the accepted order among both gods and mortals. They’re patrons of thieves, scoundrels, gamblers, rebels, and liberators. Their clerics are a disruptive force in the world, puncturing pride, mocking tyrants, stealing from the rich, freeing captives, and flouting hollow traditions. They prefer subterfuge, pranks, deception, and theft rather than direct confrontation.</p>
			<h5>Trickery Domain Spells</h5>
			<table>
				<thead>
					<tr><td>Sorcerer Level</td><td>Spells</td></tr>
				</thead>
				<tr><td>1rd</td><td><em>charm person, disguise self</em></td></tr>
				<tr><td>3rd</td><td><em>mirror image, pass without trace</em></td></tr>
				<tr><td>5th</td><td><em>blink, dispel magic</em></td></tr>
				<tr><td>7th</td><td><em>dimension door, polymorph</em></td></tr>
				<tr><td>9th</td><td><em>dominate person, modify memory</em></td></tr>
			</table>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>Clerics of Trickery Domain are a disruptive force in the world, puncturing pride, mocking tyrants, stealing from the rich, freeing captives, and flouting hollow traditions.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CHARM_PERSON" level="1" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DISGUISE_SELF" level="1" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MIRROR_IMAGE" level="3" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PASS_WITHOUT_TRACE" level="3" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BLINK" level="5" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DISPEL_MAGIC" level="5" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DIMENSION_DOOR" level="7" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_POLYMORPH" level="7" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DOMINATE_PERSON" level="9" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MODIFY_MEMORY" level="9" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="War Domain" type="Archetype Feature" source="Player’s Handbook" id="ID_WOTC_UA20150406_PHB_ARCHETYPE_FAVORED_SOUL_WAR_DOMAIN">
		<supports>Favored Soul Divine Domain</supports>
		<description>
			<p>War has many manifestations. It can make heroes of ordinary people. It can be desperate and horrific, with acts of cruelty and cowardice eclipsing instances of excellence and courage. In either case, the gods of war watch over warriors and reward them for their great deeds. The clerics of such gods excel in battle, inspiring others to fight the good fight or offering acts of violence as prayers. Gods of war include champions of honor and chivalry (such as Torm, Heironeous, and Kiri- Jolith) as well as gods of destruction and pillage (such as Erythnul, the Fury, Gruumsh, and Ares) and gods of conquest and domination (such as Bane, Hextor, and Maglubiyet). Other war gods (such as Tempus, Nike, and Nuada) take a more neutral stance, promoting war in all its manifestations and supporting warriors in any circumstance.</p>
			<h5>War Domain Spells</h5>
			<table>
				<thead>
					<tr><td>Sorcerer Level</td><td>Spells</td></tr>
				</thead>
				<tr><td>1rd</td><td><em>divine favor, shield of faith</em></td></tr>
				<tr><td>3rd</td><td><em>magic weapon, spiritual weapon</em></td></tr>
				<tr><td>5th</td><td><em>crusader’s mantle, spirit guardians</em></td></tr>
				<tr><td>7th</td><td><em>freedom of movement, stoneskin</em></td></tr>
				<tr><td>9th</td><td><em>flame strike, hold monster</em></td></tr>
			</table>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>The clerics of War Domain excel in battle, inspiring others to fight the good fight or offering acts of violence as prayers.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DIVINE_FAVOR" level="1" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SHIELD_OF_FAITH" level="1" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MAGIC_WEAPON" level="3" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SPIRITUAL_WEAPON" level="3" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CRUSADERS_MANTLE" level="5" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SPIRIT_GUARDIANS" level="5" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FREEDOM_OF_MOVEMENT" level="7" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_STONESKIN" level="7" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FLAME_STRIKE" level="9" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HOLD_MONSTER" level="9" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Death Domain" type="Archetype Feature" source="Dungeon Master’s Guide" id="ID_WOTC_UA20150406_DMG_ARCHETYPE_FAVORED_SOUL_DEATH_DOMAIN">
		<supports>Favored Soul Divine Domain</supports>
		<description>
			<p>The Death domain is concerned with the forces that cause death, as well as the negative energy that gives rise to undead creatures. Deities such as Chemosh, Myrkul, and Wee Jas are patrons of necromancers, death knights, liches, mummy lords, and vampires. Gods of the Death domain also embody murder (Anubis, Bhaal, and Pyremius), pain (Iuz or Loviatar), disease or poison (Incabulos, Talona, or Morgion), and the underworld (Hades and Hel).</p>
			<h5>War Domain Spells</h5>
			<table>
				<thead>
					<tr><td>Sorcerer Level</td><td>Spells</td></tr>
				</thead>
				<tr><td>1rd</td><td><em>false life, ray of sickness</em></td></tr>
				<tr><td>3rd</td><td><em>blindness/deafness, ray of enfeeblement</em></td></tr>
				<tr><td>5th</td><td><em>animate dead, vampiric touch</em></td></tr>
				<tr><td>7th</td><td><em>blight, death ward</em></td></tr>
				<tr><td>9th</td><td><em>antilife shell, cloudkill</em></td></tr>
			</table>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>The Death domain is concerned with the forces that cause death, as well as the negative energy that gives rise to undead creatures.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FALSE_LIFE" level="1" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_RAY_OF_SICKNESS" level="1" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BLINDNESS_DEAFNESS" level="3" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_RAY_OF_ENFEEBLEMENT" level="3" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ANIMATE_DEAD" level="5" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_VAMPIRIC_TOUCH" level="5" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BLIGHT" level="7" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DEATH_WARD" level="7" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ANTILIFE_SHELL" level="9" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CLOUDKILL" level="9" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Arcana Domain" type="Archetype Feature" source="Sword Coast Adventurer’s Guide" id="ID_WOTC_UA20150406_SCAG_ARCHETYPE_FAVORED_SOUL_ARCANA_DOMAIN">
		<supports>Favored Soul Divine Domain</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Magic is an energy that suffuses the multiverse and that fuels both destruction and creation. Gods of the Arcana domain know the secrets and potential of magic intimately. For some of these gods, magical knowledge is a great responsibility that comes with a special understanding of the nature of reality. Other gods of Arcana see magic as pure power, to be used as its wielder sees fit.</p>
			<p class="indent">The gods of this domain are often associated with knowledge, as learning and arcane power tend to go hand-in-hand. In the Realms, deities of this domain include Azuth and Mystra, as well as Corellon Larethian of the elven pantheon. In other worlds, this domain includes Hecate, Math Mathonwy, and Isis; the triple moon gods of Solinari, Lunitari, and Nuitari of Krynn; and Boccob, Vecna, and WeeJas of Greyhawk.</p>
			<h5>ARCANA DOMAIN SPELLS</h5>
			<table>
				<thead>
					<tr><td>Sorcerer Level</td><td>Spells</td></tr>
				</thead>
				<tr><td>1st</td><td><em>detect magic, magic missile</em></td></tr>
				<tr><td>3rd</td><td><em>magic weapon, Nystul's magic aura</em></td></tr>
				<tr><td>5th</td><td><em>dispel magic, magic circle</em></td></tr>
				<tr><td>7th</td><td><em>arcane eye, Leomund's secret chest</em></td></tr>
				<tr><td>9th</td><td><em>planar binding, teleportation circle</em></td></tr>
			</table>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>Magic is an energy that suffuses the multiverse and that fuels both destruction and creation.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DETECT_MAGIC" level="1" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MAGIC_MISSILE" level="1" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MAGIC_WEAPON" level="3" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_NYSTULS_MAGIC_AURA" level="3" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DISPEL_MAGIC" level="5" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MAGIC_CIRCLE" level="5" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ARCANE_EYE" level="7" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_LEOMUNDS_SECRET_CHEST" level="7" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PLANAR_BINDING" level="9" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_TELEPORTATION_CIRCLE" level="9" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Forge Domain" type="Archetype Feature" source="Xanathar’s Guide to Everything" id="ID_WOTC_UA20150406_XGTE_ARCHETYPE_FAVORED_SOUL_FORGE_DOMAIN">
		<supports>Favored Soul Divine Domain</supports>
		<description>
			<p>The gods of the forge are patrons of artisans who work with metal, from a humble blacksmith who keeps a village in horseshoes and plow blades to the mighty elf artisan whose diamond-tipped arrows of mithral have felled demon lords. The gods of the forge teach that, with patience and hard work, even the most intractable metal can be transformed from a lump of ore to a beautifully wrought object. Clerics of these deities search for objects lost to the forces of darkness, liberate mines overrun by orcs, and uncover rare and wondrous materials necessary to create potent magic items. Followers of these gods take great pride in their work, and they are willing to craft and use heavy armor and powerful weapons to protect them. Deities of this domain include Gond, Reorx, Onatar, Moradin, Hephaestus, and Goibhniu</p>
			<h5>FORGE DOMAIN SPELLS</h5>
			<table>
				<thead>
					<tr><td>Sorcerer Level</td><td>Spells</td></tr>
				</thead>
				<tr><td>1st</td><td><em>identify, searing smite</em></td></tr>
				<tr><td>3rd</td><td><em>heat metal, magic weapon</em></td></tr>
				<tr><td>5th</td><td><em>elemental weapon, protection from energy</em></td></tr>
				<tr><td>7th</td><td><em>fabricate, wall of fire</em></td></tr> 
				<tr><td>9th</td><td><em>animate objects, creation</em></td></tr>
			</table>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>The gods of the forge are patrons of artisans who work with metal, from a humble blacksmith who keeps a village in horseshoes and plow blades to the mighty elf artisan whose diamond-tipped arrows of mithral have felled demon lords.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_IDENTIFY" level="1" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SEARING_SMITE" level="1" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HEAT_METAL" level="3" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MAGIC_WEAPON" level="3" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ELEMENTAL_WEAPON" level="5" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PROTECTION_FROM_ENERGY" level="5" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FABRICATE" level="7" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_WALL_OF_FIRE" level="7" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ANIMATE_OBJECTS" level="9" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CREATION" level="9" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Grave Domain" type="Archetype Feature" source="Xanathar’s Guide to Everything" id="ID_WOTC_UA20150406_XGTE_ARCHETYPE_FAVORED_SOUL_GRAVE_DOMAIN">
		<supports>Favored Soul Divine Domain</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Gods of the grave watch over the line between life and death. To these deities, death and the afterlife are a foundational part of the multiverse. To desecrate the peace of the dead is an abomination. Deities of the grave include Kelemvor, Wee jas, the ancestral spirits of the Undying Court, Hades, Anubis, and Osiris. Followers of these deities seek to put wandering spirits to rest, destroy the undead, and ease the suffering of the dying. Their magic also allows them to stave off death for a time. particularly for a person who still has some great work to accomplish in the world. This is a delay of death, not a denial of it, for death will eventually get its due.</p>
			<h5>GRAVE DOMAIN SPELLS</h5>
			<table>
				<thead>
					<tr><td>Sorcerer Level</td><td>Spells</td></tr>
				</thead>
				<tr><td>1st</td><td><em>bane, false life</em></td></tr>
				<tr><td>3rd</td><td><em>gentle repose, ray of enfeeblement</em></td></tr>
				<tr><td>5th</td><td><em>revivify, vampiric touch</em></td></tr>
				<tr><td>7th</td><td><em>blight, death ward</em></td></tr>
				<tr><td>9th</td><td><em>antilife shell, raise dead</em></td></tr>
			</table>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>Gods of the grave watch over the line between life and death. To these deities, death and the afterlife are a foundational part of the multiverse. To desecrate the peace of the dead is an abomination.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BANE" level="1" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FALSE_LIFE" level="1" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GENTLE_REPOSE" level="3" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_RAY_OF_ENFEEBLEMENT" level="3" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_REVIVIFY" level="5" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_VAMPIRIC_TOUCH" level="5" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BLIGHT" level="7" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DEATH_WARD" level="7" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ANTILIFE_SHELL" level="9" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_RAISE_DEAD" level="9" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Entropy Domain" type="Archetype Feature" source="Xanathar’s Lost Notes to Everything Else" id="ID_WOTC_UA20150406_XLN_ARCHETYPE_FAVORED_SOUL_ENTROPY_DOMAIN">
		<supports>Favored Soul Divine Domain</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Heretics preach of a void at the center of the universe that dying gods created to devour the Weave. The necrotic energy it emits is called “Entropy”: a potent force that clerics can harness to shield themselves from magic and annihilate arcane casters. The chained god Tharizdun claims this domain, while in Chessenta, a giant sphere of annihilation is worshipped as an aspect of Entropy itself. Cultists who wield the power go by many names: thaumatoclasts, entropomancers, or entropists.</p>
			<h5>ENTROPY DOMAIN SPELLS</h5>
			<table>
				<thead>
					<tr><td>Sorcerer Level</td><td>Spells</td></tr>
				</thead>
				<tr><td>1st</td><td><em>detect magic, inflict wounds</em></td></tr>
				<tr><td>3rd</td><td><em>gentle repose, spiritual weapon</em></td></tr>
				<tr><td>5th</td><td><em>dispel magic, protection from energy</em></td></tr>
				<tr><td>7th</td><td><em>blight, death ward</em></td></tr>
				<tr><td>9th</td><td><em>circle of power, hallow</em></td></tr>
			</table>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>Heretics preach of a void at the center of the universe that dying gods created to devour the Weave.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DETECT_MAGIC" level="1" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_INFLICT_WOUNDS" level="1" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GENTLE_REPOSE" level="3" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SPIRITUAL_WEAPON" level="3" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DISPEL_MAGIC" level="5" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PROTECTION_FROM_ENERGY" level="5" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BLIGHT" level="7" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DEATH_WARD" level="7" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CIRCLE_OF_POWER" level="9" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HALLOW" level="9" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Survival Domain" type="Archetype Feature" source="Xanathar’s Lost Notes to Everything Else" id="ID_WOTC_UA20150406_XLN_ARCHETYPE_FAVORED_SOUL_SURVIVAL_DOMAIN">
		<supports>Favored Soul Divine Domain</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Clerics and shamans of primitive tribes living in harsh environments have no greater mission than ensuring the survival of their tribes. The gods of survival often have other domains in similar realms, such as life or nature. The worshippers who work within the Survival domain, however, are much more primal and brutal than their counterparts.</p>
			<p class="indent">The gods of primitive and uncivilized races are most likely to hold this domain: lizardfolk god Semuanya and orc goddess Luthic are prime examples of deities whose clerics embrace the Survival domain. They are more likely to remain in their territories, nurturing and protecting their flocks, but fighting fiercely when a threat invades their lairs.</p>
			<h6>SURVIVAL DOMAIN SPELLS</h6>
			<table>
				<thead>
					<tr><td>Sorcerer Level</td><td>Spells</td></tr>
				</thead>
				<tr><td>1st</td><td><em>create or destroy water, false life</em></td></tr>
				<tr><td>3rd</td><td><em>locate animals or plants, prayer of healing</em></td></tr>
				<tr><td>5th</td><td><em>fear, protection from energy</em></td></tr>
				<tr><td>7th</td><td><em>death ward, dominate beast</em></td></tr>
				<tr><td>9th</td><td><em>antilife shell, greater restoration</em></td></tr>
			</table>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>Clerics and shamans of primitive tribes living in harsh environments have no greater mission than ensuring the survival of their tribes.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CREATE_OR_DESTROY_WATER" level="1" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FALSE_LIFE" level="1" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_LOCATE_ANIMALS_OR_PLANTS" level="3" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PRAYER_OF_HEALING" level="3" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FEAR" level="5" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PROTECTION_FROM_ENERGY" level="5" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DEATH_WARD" level="7" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DOMINATE_BEAST" level="7" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ANTILIFE_SHELL" level="9" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GREATER_RESTORATION" level="9" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Blood Domain" type="Archetype Feature" source="Critical Role: Tal’Dorei Campaign Setting" id="ID_WOTC_UA20150406_TDCS_ARCHETYPE_FAVORED_SOUL_BLOOD_DOMAIN">
		<supports>Favored Soul Divine Domain</supports>
		<description>
			<p>Originally developed in Wildemount by the Claret Orders, the Blood domain centers around the understanding of the natural life force within one’s own physical body. The power of blood is the power of sacrifice, the balance of life and death, and the spirit’s anchor within the mortal shell. The Gods of Blood seek to tap into the connection between body and soul through divine means, exploit the hidden reserves of will within one’s own vitality, and even manipulate or corrupt the body of others through these secret rites of crimson. Almost any neutral or evil deity can claim some influence over the secrets of blood magic and this domain, while the gods who watch from more moral realms shun its use beyond extenuating circumstance.</p>
			<p class="indent">When casting divine spells as a Blood Domain cleric, consider ways to occasionally flavor your descriptions to tailor the magic’s effect on the opponent’s blood and vitality. Hold person might involve locking a target’s body into place from the blood stream out, preventing them from moving. Cure wounds may feature the controlling of blood like a needle and thread to close lacerations. Guardian of faith could be a floating, crimson spirit of dripping viscera who watches the vicinity with burning red eyes. Have fun with the themes!</p>
			<h5>Blood Domain Spells</h5>
			<table>
				<thead>
					<tr><td>Sorcerer Level</td><td>Spells</td></tr>
				</thead>
				<tr><td>1st</td><td><em>sleep, ray of sickness</em></td></tr>
				<tr><td>3rd</td><td><em>ray of enfeeblement, crown of madness</em></td></tr>
				<tr><td>5th</td><td><em>haste, slow</em></td></tr>
				<tr><td>7th</td><td><em>blight, stoneskin</em></td></tr>
				<tr><td>9th</td><td><em>dominate person, hold monster</em></td></tr>
			</table>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>Originally developed in Wildemount by the Claret Orders, the Blood domain centers around the understanding of the natural life force within one’s own physical body.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SLEEP" level="1" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_RAY_OF_SICKNESS" level="1" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_RAY_OF_ENFEEBLEMENT" level="3" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CROWN_OF_MADNESS" level="3" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HASTE" level="5" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SLOW" level="5" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BLIGHT" level="7" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_STONESKIN" level="7" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DOMINATE_PERSON" level="9" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HOLD_MONSTER" level="9" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="City Domain" type="Archetype Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana: Modern Magic" id="ID_WOTC_UA20150406_UA20150803_ARCHETYPE_FAVORED_SOUL_CITY_DOMAIN">
		<supports>Favored Soul Divine Domain</supports>
		<description>
			<p>The City domain is concerned with the citizenry, commerce, traffic, and even architecture of modern civilization. In the eyes of a cleric of the city, the center of modern life is a sense and spirit of community, and the gravest enemies of the city are those who seek to harm the common weal of its citizens.</p>
			<p class="indent">New spells introduced for the City domain are marked with an asterisk and detailed in the “New Spells” section. For all other spells, see the <i>Player’s Handbook</i>.</p>
			<h5>City Domain Spells</h5>
			<table>
				<thead>
					<tr><td>Sorcerer Level</td><td>Spells</td></tr>
				</thead>
				<tr><td>1st</td><td><em>comprehend languages, remote access*</em></td></tr>
				<tr><td>3rd</td><td><em>find vehicle*, heat metal</em></td></tr>
				<tr><td>5th</td><td><em>lightning bolt, protection from ballistics*</em></td></tr>
				<tr><td>7th</td><td><em>locate creature, synchronicity*</em></td></tr>
				<tr><td>9th</td><td><em>commune with city*, shutdown*</em></td></tr>
			</table>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>The City domain is concerned with the citizenry, commerce, traffic, and even architecture of modern civilization.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_COMPREHEND_LANGUAGES" level="1" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_WOTC_UA20150803_SPELL_REMOTE_ACCESS" level="1" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_WOTC_UA20150803_SPELL_FIND_VEHICLE" level="3" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HEAT_METAL" level="3" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_LIGHTNING_BOLT" level="5" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_WOTC_UA20150803_SPELL_PROTECTION_FROM_BALLISTICS" level="5" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_LOCATE_CREATURE" level="7" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_WOTC_UA20150803_SPELL_SYNCHRONICITY" level="7" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_WOTC_UA20150803_SPELL_COMMUNE_WITH_CITY" level="9" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_WOTC_UA20150803_SPELL_SHUTDOWN" level="9" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Order Domain" type="Archetype Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana: Order Domain" id="ID_WOTC_UA20150406_UA20180409_ARCHETYPE_FAVORED_SOUL_ORDER_DOMAIN">
		<supports>Favored Soul Divine Domain</supports>
		<description>
			<p>The Order domain represents discipline, as well as service to a society or an institution, whether that service is rendered in obedience to or enforcement of the law—civil, religious, or both. Gods on many worlds grant access to this domain, including Bane, Tyr, Majere, Erathis, Pholtus, Wee Jas, Aureon, Maglubiyet, Nuada, Athena, Anubis, Forseti, and Asmodeus.</p>
			<p class="indent">The ideal of order is obedience to the law above all else, rather than to a specific individual or the passing influence of emotion or popular rule. Clerics of order are typically concerned with how things are done, rather than whether an action’s results are just. Following the law and obeying its edicts is critical, especially when it benefits these clerics and their deities.</p>
			<p class="indent">More importantly, law establishes hierarchies. Those selected by the law to lead must be obeyed. Those who obey must do so to the best of their ability. In this manner, law creates an intricate web of obligations that allows society to forge order and security in a chaotic multiverse.</p>
			<h5>Order Domain Spells</h5>
			<table>
				<thead>
					<tr><td>Sorcerer Level</td><td>Spells</td></tr>
				</thead>
				<tr><td>1st</td><td><em>command, heroism</em></td></tr>
				<tr><td>3rd</td><td><em>hold person, zone of truth</em></td></tr>
				<tr><td>5th</td><td><em>mass healing word, slow</em></td></tr>
				<tr><td>7th</td><td><em>compulsion, locate creature</em></td></tr>
				<tr><td>9th</td><td><em>commune, dominate person</em></td></tr>
			</table>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>The Order domain represents discipline, as well as service to a society or an institution, whether that service is rendered in obedience to or enforcement of the law—civil, religious, or both.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_COMMAND" level="1" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HEROISM" level="1" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HOLD_PERSON" level="3" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ZONE_OF_TRUTH" level="3" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MASS_HEALING_WORD" level="5" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SLOW" level="5" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_COMPULSION" level="7" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_LOCATE_CREATURE" level="7" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_COMMUNE" level="9" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DOMINATE_PERSON" level="9" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Protection Domain" type="Archetype Feature" source="Unearthed Arcana: Cleric: Divine Domains" id="ID_WOTC_UA20150406_UA20161121_ARCHETYPE_FAVORED_SOUL_PROTECTION_DOMAIN">
		<supports>Favored Soul Divine Domain</supports>
		<description>
			<p>The protection domain is the purview of deities who charge their followers to shield the weak from the strong. The gods’ faithful dwell in villages and towns on the borderlands, where they help bolster defenses and seek out evils to defeat. These gods believe that a strong shield and a suit of armor is the best defense against evil, second only to a stout mace on hand to respond to any attacks in kind. Deities who grant this domain include Helm, Ilmater, Torm, Tyr, Heironeous, St. Cuthbert, Paladine, Dol Dorn, the Silver Flame, Bahamut, Yondalla, Athena, and Odin.</p>
			<h5>Order Domain Spells</h5>
			<table>
				<thead>
					<tr><td>Sorcerer Level</td><td>Spells</td></tr>
				</thead>
				<tr><td>1st</td><td><em>compelled duel, protection from evil and good</em></td></tr>
				<tr><td>3rd</td><td><em>aid, protection from poison</em></td></tr>
				<tr><td>5th</td><td><em>protection from energy, slow</em></td></tr>
				<tr><td>7th</td><td><em>guardian of faith, Otiluke’s resilient sphere</em></td></tr> 
				<tr><td>9th</td><td><em>antilife shell, wall of force</em></td></tr>
			</table>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>The protection domain is the purview of deities who charge their followers to shield the weak from the strong.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_COMPELLED_DUEL" level="1" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PROTECTION_FROM_EVIL_AND_GOOD" level="1" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_AID" level="3" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PROTECTION_FROM_POISON" level="3" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PROTECTION_FROM_ENERGY" level="5" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SLOW" level="5" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GUARDIAN_OF_FAITH" level="7" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_OTILUKES_RESILIENT_SPHERE" level="7" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ANTILIFE_SHELL" level="9" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_WALL_OF_FORCE" level="9" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Order Domain" type="Archetype Feature" source="Guildmasters’ Guide to Ravnica" id="ID_WOTC_UA20150406_GGTR_ARCHETYPE_FAVORED_SOUL_ORDER_DOMAIN">
		<supports>Favored Soul Divine Domain</supports>
		<description>
			<p>The Order domain represents discipline, as well as service to a society or an institution, whether that service is rendered in obedience to or enforcement of the law—civil, religious, or both. Gods on many worlds grant access to this domain, including Bane, Tyr, Majere, Erathis, Pholtus, Wee Jas, Aureon, Maglubiyet, Nuada, Athena, Anubis, Forseti, and Asmodeus.</p>
			<p class="indent">The ideal of order is obedience to the law above all else, rather than to a specific individual or the passing influence of emotion or popular rule. Clerics of order are typically concerned with how things are done, rather than whether an action’s results are just. Following the law and obeying its edicts is critical, especially when it benefits these clerics and their deities.</p>
			<p class="indent">More importantly, law establishes hierarchies. Those selected by the law to lead must be obeyed. Those who obey must do so to the best of their ability. In this manner, law creates an intricate web of obligations that allows society to forge order and security in a chaotic multiverse.</p>
			<h5>Order Domain Spells</h5>
			<table>
				<thead>
					<tr><td>Sorcerer Level</td><td>Spells</td></tr>
				</thead>
				<tr><td>1st</td><td><em>command, heroism</em></td></tr>
				<tr><td>3rd</td><td><em>hold person, zone of truth</em></td></tr>
				<tr><td>5th</td><td><em>mass healing word, slow</em></td></tr>
				<tr><td>7th</td><td><em>compulsion, locate creature</em></td></tr>
				<tr><td>9th</td><td><em>commune, dominate person</em></td></tr>
			</table>
		</description>
		<sheet>
			<description>The Order domain represents discipline, as well as service to a society or an institution, whether that service is rendered in obedience to or enforcement of the law—civil, religious, or both.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_COMMAND" level="1" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HEROISM" level="1" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HOLD_PERSON" level="3" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ZONE_OF_TRUTH" level="3" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MASS_HEALING_WORD" level="5" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SLOW" level="5" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_COMPULSION" level="7" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_LOCATE_CREATURE" level="7" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_COMMUNE" level="9" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DOMINATE_PERSON" level="9" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Ambition Domain" type="Archetype Feature" source="Plane Shift: Amonkhet" id="ID_WOTC_UA20150406_PSA_ARCHETYPE_FAVORED_SOUL_AMBITION_DOMAIN">
		<supports>Favored Soul Divine Domain</supports>
		<description>
            <p>Bontu has fully embraced this dictum, and though she expends little effort in teaching it, she surely leads by example. Her viziers subtly plant the seeds that flower into the ambition the God-Pharaoh desires. Through insinuation, they remind acolytes and initiates alike that achieving one’s place in the afterlife at the expense of others is not shameful, but is proof of the initiate’s determination and drive. Nothing is more important than that drive, they suggest—not the bonds of a crop, not friendship or love. Not even devotion to a deity.</p>
			<h5>Ambition Domain Spells</h5>
			<table>
				<thead>
					<tr><td>Sorcerer Level</td><td>Spells</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td>1st</td><td><em>bane, disguise self</em></td></tr>
                <tr><td>3rd</td><td><em>mirror image, ray of enfeeblement</em></td></tr>
                <tr><td>5th</td><td><em>bestow curse, vampiric touch</em></td></tr>
                <tr><td>7th</td><td><em>death ward, dimension door</em></td></tr>
                <tr><td>9th</td><td><em>dominate person, modify memory</em></td></tr>
            </table>
		</description>
        <setters>
            <set name="sourceUrl">http://dnd.wizards.com/articles/features/plane-shift-amonkhet</set>
        </setters>
		<sheet>
            <description>The ambition domain is granted to those who follow the teachings of the God-Pharaoh Bontu.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BANE" level="1" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DISGUISE_SELF" level="1" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MIRROR_IMAGE" level="3" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_RAY_OF_ENFEEBLEMENT" level="3" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BESTOW_CURSE" level="5" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_VAMPIRIC_TOUCH" level="5" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DEATH_WARD" level="7" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DIMENSION_DOOR" level="7" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DOMINATE_PERSON" level="9" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MODIFY_MEMORY" level="9" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Solidarity Domain" type="Archetype Feature" source="Plane Shift: Amonkhet" id="ID_WOTC_UA20150406_PSA_ARCHETYPE_FAVORED_SOUL_SOLIDARITY_DOMAIN">
		<supports>Favored Soul Divine Domain</supports>
		<description>
            <p>The God-Pharaoh expects those he welcomes into the afterlife to desire it above all other pleasures and achievements, and for them to show their dedication, passion, and fervor through their actions. Hazoret is charged with cultivating this Solidarity in the initiates who come under her care, and she has undertaken the task with appropriate enthusiasm. She recognizes, however, that the best way to teach Solidarity is by demonstrating it.</p>
			<h5>Solidarity Domain Spells</h5>
			<table>
				<thead>
					<tr><td>Sorcerer Level</td><td>Spells</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td>1st</td><td><em>bless, guiding bolt</em></td></tr>
                <tr><td>3rd</td><td><em>aid, warding bond</em></td></tr>
                <tr><td>5th</td><td><em>beacon of hope, crusader’s mantle</em></td></tr>
                <tr><td>7th</td><td><em>aura of life, guardian of faith</em></td></tr>
                <tr><td>9th</td><td><em>circle of power, mass cure wounds</em></td></tr>
            </table>
		</description>
        <setters>
            <set name="sourceUrl">http://dnd.wizards.com/articles/features/plane-shift-amonkhet</set>
        </setters>
        <sheet>
            <description>The Solidarity domain is granted to those who follow the teachings of the God-Pharaoh Oketra.</description>
        </sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BLESS" level="1" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GUIDING_BOLT" level="1" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_AID" level="3" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_WARDING_BOND" level="3" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_BEACON_OF_HOPE" level="5" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CRUSADERS_MANTLE" level="5" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_AURA_OF_LIFE" level="7" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_GUARDIAN_OF_FAITH" level="7" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_CIRCLE_OF_POWER" level="9" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MASS_CURE_WOUNDS" level="9" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Strength Domain" type="Archetype Feature" source="Plane Shift: Amonkhet" id="ID_WOTC_UA20150406_PSA_ARCHETYPE_FAVORED_SOUL_STRENGTH_DOMAIN">
		<supports>Favored Soul Divine Domain</supports>
		<description>
            <p>It falls to Rhonas to instill this teaching in those who would enter the afterlife—but to his mind, the words themselves don’t matter. Strength can’t be taught. It must be built through practice and training. Rhonas demonstrates his teachings by his example, rather than by giving his students any kind of academic instruction. He welcomes the people of Naktamun to stand by the Hekma and watch him as he storms into the desert to battle the greatest horrors. He encourages them to observe his indomitable strength, for though they will never equal it, they can aspire to mimicry. He invites them to scrutinize every move and practice what they see</p>
			<h5>Strength Domain Spells</h5>
			<table>
				<thead>
					<tr><td>Sorcerer Level</td><td>Spells</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td>1st</td><td><em>divine favor, shield of faith</em></td></tr>
                <tr><td>3rd</td><td><em>enhance ability, protection from poison</em></td></tr>
                <tr><td>5th</td><td><em>haste, protection from energy</em></td></tr>
                <tr><td>7th</td><td><em>dominate beast, stoneskin</em></td></tr>
                <tr><td>9th</td><td><em>destructive wave, insect plague</em></td></tr>
            </table>
		</description>
        <setters>
            <set name="sourceUrl">http://dnd.wizards.com/articles/features/plane-shift-amonkhet</set>
        </setters>
        <sheet>
            <description>The Strength domain is granted to those who follow the teachings of the God-Pharaoh Rhonas.</description>
        </sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DIVINE_FAVOR" level="1" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SHIELD_OF_FAITH" level="1" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_ENHANCE_ABILITY" level="3" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PROTECTION_FROM_POISON" level="3" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HASTE" level="5" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_PROTECTION_FROM_ENERGY" level="5" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DOMINATE_BEAST" level="7" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_STONESKIN" level="7" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DESCTRUCTIVE_WAVE" level="9" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_INSECT_PLAGUE" level="9" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
		</rules>
	</element>

	<element name="Zeal Domain" type="Archetype Feature" source="Plane Shift: Amonkhet" id="ID_WOTC_UA20150406_PSA_ARCHETYPE_FAVORED_SOUL_ZEAL_DOMAIN">
		<supports>Favored Soul Divine Domain</supports>
		<description>
            <p>The God-Pharaoh expects those he welcomes into the afterlife to desire it above all other pleasures and achievements, and for them to show their dedication, passion, and fervor through their actions. Hazoret is charged with cultivating this zeal in the initiates who come under her care, and she has undertaken the task with appropriate enthusiasm. She recognizes, however, that the best way to teach zeal is by demonstrating it.</p>
			<h5>Zeal Domain Spells</h5>
			<table>
				<thead>
					<tr><td>Sorcerer Level</td><td>Spells</td></tr>
                </thead>
                <tr><td>1st</td><td><em>searing smite, thunderous smite</em></td></tr>
                <tr><td>3rd</td><td><em>magic weapon, shatter</em></td></tr>
                <tr><td>5th</td><td><em>haste, fireball</em></td></tr>
                <tr><td>7th</td><td><em>fire shield (warm shield only), freedom of movement</em></td></tr>
                <tr><td>9th</td><td><em>destructive wave, flame strike</em></td></tr>
            </table>
		</description>
        <setters>
            <set name="sourceUrl">http://dnd.wizards.com/articles/features/plane-shift-amonkhet</set>
        </setters>
        <sheet>
            <description>The zeal domain is granted to those who follow the teachings of the God-Pharaoh Hazoret.</description>
        </sheet>
		<rules>
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SEARING_SMITE" level="1" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_THUNDEROUS_SMITE" level="1" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_MAGIC_WEAPON" level="3" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_SHATTER" level="3" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_HASTE" level="5" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FIREBALL" level="5" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FIRE_SHIELD" level="7" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FREEDOM_OF_MOVEMENT" level="7" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_DESCTRUCTIVE_WAVE" level="9" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
			<grant type="Spell" id="ID_PHB_SPELL_FLAME_STRIKE" level="9" spellcasting="Sorcerer" />
		</rules>
	</element>
</elements>